<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IgniteSTEM</title>
    <description>Bring Hackathons, Maker Faires and Design Thinking to your students.
</description>
    <link>http://ignitestem.org/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://ignitestem.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 21:21:09 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 21:21:09 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.5.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>IgniteSTEM 2018 Teacher Award</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;IgniteSTEM is pleased to present the 2018 IgniteSTEM Teacher Award to Kevin Ruane of Ocean Township Elementary School. Kevin has been a driving force behind innovating in STEM education at his elementary school, where he started a maker space club in 2015 that has since grown and spread to all three other elementary schools in the Ocean Township School District. A valuable member of the IgniteSTEM community since 2016, Kevin has attended all three IgniteSTEM NYC flagship conferences, and has used what he has learned at the conference to spearhead and invigorate STEM education not only for students in his own classroom and maker space club, but in the entire district as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin also uses the 20 percent time or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geniushour.com/what-is-genius-hour/&quot;&gt;“genius hour”&lt;/a&gt;  in his everyday curriculum , which encourages students to learn more deeply about their passions and interests. He has also been instrumental in the rewrite of the district’s elementary science curriculum in accordance to the guidelines of NGSS. His next goal is to start an elementary hackathon for students in his district, which he plans to put the IgniteSTEM Teacher Award grant towards accomplishing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin Ruane is an Elementary School teacher in the Ocean Township School District in New Jersey, and can be reached at kruane@oceanschools.org. Congratulations Kevin on your accomplishments and incredible impact on your community! IgniteSTEM looks forward to hearing about, learning from, and supporting your ongoing and future initiatives!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 05:39:13 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://ignitestem.org/2018/05/18/ignitestem-2018-teacher-award.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://ignitestem.org/2018/05/18/ignitestem-2018-teacher-award.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
